Guide to the Charles N. Fifer Photographs PC0124
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles N. Fifer Photographs
1901-1995
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Fifer, Charles N., 1922-
PC0124
1 Linear Feet 4 boxes
Collection contains photographs of Charles and Norma Fifer, 1958-92; faculty in the Stanford Department of English, 1970s-1995; Stanford overseas campuses and students in England 1972 (Cliveden campus) and France (Tours campus) 1966; and Charles Fifer during his own student days, 1940s-50s. Stanford faculty (and their wives) represented include Maclin Guerard, Richard Scowcroft, Claude Simpson, Albert Guerard, and George and Libbie Sensabaugh. Collection also includes a few sketches (watercolor and other media) of Cliveden, 1971-72.
Access to Collection
Open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Charles N. Fifer earned his BA and MA at Northwestern University and his Ph.D. (1954) at Yale. He taught at Lawrence College and the University of Illinois before joining the faculty in the Department of English at Stanford University in 1956.
Scope and Contents
Collection contains photographs of Charles and Norma Fifer, 1958-92; faculty in the Stanford Department of English, 1970s-1995; Stanford overseas campuses and students in England 1972 (Cliveden campus) and France (Tours campus) 1966; and Charles Fifer during his own student days, 1940s-50s. Stanford faculty (and their wives) represented include Maclin Guerard, Richard Scowcroft, Claude Simpson, Albert Guerard, and George and Libbie Sensabaugh. Collection also includes a few sketches (watercolor and other media) of Cliveden, 1971-72.
Fifer, Charles N., 1922-
- Photographs
  - Charles Fifer in his student days, 1940s-50s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Charles and Norma Fifer and family photographs, 1958-59 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Charles and Norma Fifer and family photographs, 1960, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Charles and Norma Fifer and family photographs, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Charles and Norma Fifer and family photographs, 1980s, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Charles and Norma Fifer and family photographs, undated and miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charles and Norma Fifer and family photographs – gardens and outdoor shots (no people) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Labeled: VCR celebration, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Portrait of Charles Fifer by Raymond Thatcher ca. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Junipero House, Wilbur Hall – student RAs?, 1961-62 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - English department faculty, b/w images, (includes Maclin Guerard, Richard Scowcroft, Claude Simpson, and Albert Guerard) [note: some are dated 1980 but that may not be correct as one person so identified died in 1976 (Simpson)] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - English department faculty at social events, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - English department faculty at social events, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - English department faculty, miscellaneous, 1989 and n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - George and Libbie Sensabaugh, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cliveden (Stanford in England) 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Overseas Studies, miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Overseas Studies student group, Tours, France, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Overseas Studies student group, Cliveden?, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Sketches (watercolor and other media) of Cliveden 1971-72 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Additional materials, undated; Accession ARCH.2009-069
  - Slides of Clivedon and tours (Box 1)
- Additional materials, Accession ARCH-2015-081
  - Black and white prints by Gary Massoni, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clipping from Stanford Daily, Clench Brooks and Charles Fifer, 1964-1-29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Rachel L. Andrews from Bert Coolidge, 1901-3-17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Larry Friedlander, Professor of English, undated (Box 2)